Guide to the Native American oral histories audio recordings 1954-1993
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
Native American oral histories audio recordings
1954-1993
University of Utah Libraries, Special Collections Audio Visual Archives Special Collections 295 South 1500 East Salt Lake City, Utah 84112-0860 (801) 581-8864
A0874
American West Center
138 reel-to-reel audiotapes and 91 audiocassettes. 2 compact disc duplicates (258 CDs) of each item are available for patron use.
The Native American oral histories audio recordings (1954-1993) consists of interviews with members of various Native American tribes who discuss subjects such as land use, land boundaries, tribal history, rituals, and tribal songs. Represented groups include: Nevada Intertribal Council, Hupa, various Ute groups, Tohono O'odham, Tesuqe and Santa Ana Pueblo. The American West Center is dedicated to documenting the history of the intermountain region and surrounding areas.
Organizational History
The American West Center is a research center at the University of Utah which is affiliated with the College of Social and Behavioral Science. The Center is dedicated to providing educational and curricular support to Indian tribes, school districts, other interested organizations, and the general public through consultations, research, and publications.
The Native American oral histories audio recordings (1954-1993) consists of interviews with members of various Native American tribes who discuss subjects such as land use, land boundaries, tribal history, rituals, and tribal songs. Represented groups include: Nevada Intertribal Council, Hupa, various Ute groups, Tohono O'odham, Tesuqe and Santa Ana Pueblo.
The materials are organized by Native American tribe.
Materials must be used on-site; no use of original material, access copies will be made available for viewing. Five business days advanced notice required. Access to parts of this collection may be restricted under provisions of state or federal law, condition of the material, or by donor.
See also the Doris Duke American Indian oral history project audio recordings (A0001).
Indians of North America--Interviews; Indians of North America--West (U.S.)--Interviews; Indians of North America--History--20th century--Interviews; Indians of North America--Social life and customs; Social Classes; Sound Recordings; Oral Histories; Sound recordings
- Nevada Intertribal Council
  - June Tom, 1974 March 27; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 1)
    Interviewed and recorded by Sharon Malotte
  - Andy Garrison, 1974 March 28; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 2)
  - Frank Sam, 1974 April 04; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 3)
  - Millie Reynolds, 1974 April 18; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 4)
  - Bridgeport meeting, land problem, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 5)
    Land issues.
  - Marie Bill, 1974 March 19; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 6)
  - Ida Stewart, Louie Stewart, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 7)
  - Lemard Tylo; Marie Bill, 1974 May 19; 1974 March 27; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 8)
    Shoshone men's hand-game song and women's hand-game song.
    Interviewed and recorded by Sharon Malotte, South Fork Indian Reservation
  - Dannie Millett, 1974 January 16; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 9)
    Shoshone songs.
  - Earl Dean Horney, 1974 March 26; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 10)
  - Songs, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 11)
    Native songs
  - Native Stories, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 12)
    Side 1: "Antelope Surround Road at Golconda"; "Big Times at Owyhee"
    Side 2: "Captain Buck Preparing Willows Plants"
    Compiled by: Earl Dean Horney, David Teller, Bessie Hall, Tom Premo, Lucy Hall, and Anna Thomas.
  - Lesson 1-15; song and prayer, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 13)
    Side 1: Lesson 1-15 by B. Crum and Tom Premo. Potontsia by Lucy Hall. Indian prayer and song by John Jones.
    Side 2: Song and prayer by John Jones. Songs by Bessie Hall. Plants by Lucy Hall.
  - Frank San, Helen McGee, 1974 April 4; 1974 May 22; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 15)
  - Nellie Sanchez, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 16)
    Interviewed and recorded by Floyd A. O'Neil and Jackie Rice
  - Moapa, Nevada, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 17)
  - Irene Dick, M. Dressler, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 21)
  - Songs of Johnny Wager; hand game songs, 1955 November 30; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 22)
    Side 1: Songs of Johnny Wager, parts 1 and 2 from W. Jacobson Collection.
    Conclusion of hand-game songs by Clara Frank.
  - Rubell Miller, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 23)
  - Washo Dance Songs, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 24)
    Washo Dance Songs
    Compiled by W. D. D'Azenado
  - Songs, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 25)
    Compiled by Clara Frank, Fred Richards, and John Wager.
  - Hamilton Kizer and M. Dressler, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 26)
  - Yetta Jacke, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 27)
  - Sam Panance, 1974 June 11; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 28)
    Moapa, Nevada.
    Interviewed and recorded by Jackie Rice
  - Clifford Jake, 1974 June; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 29)
    Cedar City, Utah.
  - Harry Winnemucca, 1974 September 11; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 30)
  - Harry Winnemucca, 1974 Octoer 11; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 31)
  - Washo dance songs, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 32)
  - Dolly Silver, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 33)
    The story of how the first white men came to Nevada, four songs.
  - Helen Enos, Minnie Poole, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 34)
    Interviewed and recorded by Jean and Grace Dexter
  - Hand-game songs, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 35)
  - Alex Cleveland, 1974 May 29; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 36)
    Owyhee.
  - Indian living, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 37)
    Indian medicines, food, clothing, shelters, etc.
  - David Christy, 1974 August 16; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 38)
  - Bill James, Therian Shan, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 39)
  - Dane Christy, 1974 August 29; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 40)
  - Frank Morgan parts 1-2, 1974 September 6; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 41)
  - Albert M., undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 42)
  - Filmstrips part 1, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 43)
  - Filmstrips part 2, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 44)
  - Aunt Mamie, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 45)
  - Edith Dewey, Joe Bowers, Sam Kinney, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 46)
    Side 1: Edith Dewey and Joe Bowers.
    Side 2: Sam Kinney.
  - Raymond Stone, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 47)
  - Edith Moke, Herbert Myers, Juanita Lee, 1976 December 21; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 48)
    History of Las Vegas Colony, Moapa, Nevada.
    Interviewed and recorded by Floyd A. O'Neil, John Alley, Louella Tom, and Belinda Anderson.
  - Edith Mike, Juanita Lee, Belinda Anderson, 1976 December 21; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 49)
    Interviewed and recorded by John Alley, Louella Tom, and Floyd A. O'Neil.
  - Edith Dewey, Joe Bowers, Sam Kinney, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 50)
  - Maureen Frank, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 51)
    Southern Paiutes.
  - Guy Manning, Willie McKinney, John Dieh, Sr., 1954 November 19; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 52)
    Owyhee History, stories and songs.
  - Guy Manning, Willie McKinney, John Dick, 1954 November 19; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 53)
    Shoshone history, Shoshone songs, and Coyote legends.
  - Daisy Mike, 1977 January 02; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 54)
    Las Vegas, Nevada.
    Interviewed and recorded by Floyd A. O'Neil
  - Daisy Mike, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 55)
    Southern Paiute
  - Edith Mike, Herbert Meyers, Juanita Lee, 1976 December 21; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 56)
    History of the Las Vegas Colony, Moapa, Nevada.
    Interviewed and recorded by Louella Tom, Belinda Anderson, John Alley, and Floyd A. O'Neil.
  - Edith Mike, Juanita Lee, Belinda Anderson, 1976 December 21; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 57)
  - Daisy Mike, 1977 January 02; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel NITC 58)
- Urban Indian
  - George Howell, 1972 May 02; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel U 1)
    Interviewed and recorded by Mary Ellen Sloan
  - Indian Awareness Week at The University Of Utah, 1972 May 05; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel U 3)
    Tribalism. Six panel members: No name - Sioux, John Maestas - Pueblo, Edd Brown - Yaqui, David Jacobs - Mohawk, no name - Assiniboine, Joe Sequi - no tribe name.
  - Indian Awareness Week at the University of Utah, 1972 May 05; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel U 4)
    No name - Sioux, John Maestas - Pueblo, Edd Brown - Yaqui, David Jacobs - Mohawk, no name - Assiniboine, Joe Sequi - no tribe name.
  - Indian Awareness Week at The University Of Utah, 1972 May 04; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel U 7)
    Dennis Banks: American Indian Movement
  - Indian Awareness Week at The University Of Utah, 1972 May 04; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel U 8)
    Dennis Banks: American Indian Movement.
  - Indian Awareness Week at The University Of Utah, 1972 May 04; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel U 9)
    Intro: Gilbert Frazier, John Mackey, Dick Young.
  - Indian Awareness Week at The University Of Utah, 1972 May 04; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel U 10)
    Jerry Wilkenson from the National Indian Youth Council.
  - Indian Awareness Week at the University of Utah, 1972 May 04; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel U 11)
    Dick Young and Jerry Wilkenson from the National Indian Youth Council.
  - Indian Awareness Week at the University of Utah, 1972 May 02; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel U 12)
    Intro: Gilbert Fraiser, Leon Cook.
  - Clyde Bellecourt, Ed Benton, Stanley Snake, 1972 May 02; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel U 13)
    Urban Indian.
  - George Howell Indian Awareness Week speech, 1972 May 02; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel U 14)
    Indian minorities.
    Recorded by Mary Ellen Sloan
- Hupa
  - G. B. Nelson, 1987 January 14; Audiocassette (Cassette H 1)
  - James E. Jackson, 1987 January 15; Audiocassette (Cassette H 2)
  - James E. Jackson continued, 1987 January 15; Audiocassette (Cassette H 3)
  - Peter N. Jackson, 1988 August 23; Audiocassette (Cassette H 4)
  - Peter N. Jackson continued, 1988 August 23; Audiocassette (Cassette H 5)
  - Peter Masten, Jr., 1988 August 23; Audiocassette (Cassette H 6)
  - Richard Rickleffs, 1988 August 23; Audiocassette (Cassette H 7)
  - Wilfred Colgrone, 1988 August 14; Audiocassette (Cassette H 8)
  - C. Joe Moon, 1988 August 24; Audiocassette (Cassette H 9)
  - C. Joe Moon continued, 1988 August 24; Audiocassette (Cassette H 10)
  - Byron Nelson, Sr., 1988 August 25; Audiocassette (Cassette H 11)
  - Peter Nix, 1988 August 25; Audiocassette (Cassette H 12)
  - Gary Risling, 1988 August 25; Audiocassette (Cassette H 13)
  - Jesse Short, Robert McCoy, 1988 August 26; Audiocassette (Cassette H 14)
- Navajo
  - Virginia Smith, Sherril Burge, 1979 August 01; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel N 1)
    Oljato Trading Post.
  - Fanny Ben, 1973 January 5-6; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel N 2)
    Hard Ground Area, New Mexico.
    Interviewed and recorded by Mike Benally
  - Mike Benally, Gloria Twitchell, 1972 December 04; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel N 3)
    Interviewed and recorded by John D. Sylvester and Gregory C. Thompson in Salt Lake City, Utah.
- Southern Ute
  - Harry Richards, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel SU 1)
    Translation of Harry Richards
  - Harry Richards, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel SU 2)
  - Harry Richards, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel SU 3)
    Translation of Harry Richards.
  - Harry Richards, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel SU 4)
- Southern Ute history
  - Exploration in Southern Ute History narration, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel SUH 1)
    Narration to accompany Explorations in Southern Ute History filmstrip.
  - Explorations in Southern Ute history, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel SUH 2)
  - Southern Ute History Today narration, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel SUH 3)
    Narration to accompany Southern Ute History Today filmstrips.
- Tohono O'odham Nation
  - Patrick Johnny Franco, 1988 September 09; Audiocassette (Cassette T 1)
  - James McCarty, 1988 September 09; Audiocassette (Cassette T 2)
  - Jose Cruz Pablo, 1988 September 09; Audiocassette (Cassette T 3)
  - Lena Ramon, 1988 September 10; Audiocassette (Cassette T 4)
  - Accencion Anton, 1988 September 10; Audiocassette (Cassette T 5)
    Interviewed and recorded by Floyd A. O'Neil. Translated by Anna Anton
  - Rufina Morris, 1988 September 10; Audiocassette (Cassette T 6)
  - Peter Blaine, 1988 September 10; Audiocassette (Cassette T 7)
  - Clara "Bonnie" Price, 1988 September 13; Audiocassette (Cassette T 8)
  - Claudia Daniel, 1988 September 14; Audiocassette (Cassette T 9)
  - Tony Lopez, 1988 September 11; Audiocassette (Cassette T 10)
- Tesuque tribal history
  - Lorenzo Pino, 1992 September 14; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 1)
  - Ignacia Duran, 1992 September 14; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 2)
  - Dominguita Abeyta, 1992 September 14; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 3)
  - Lorenzo Pino, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 4)
  - Ignacia Duran, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 5)
  - Marvin Herrera, 1992 September 16; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 6)
    Interviewed and recorded by Floyd A. O'Neil and Bob Delaney
  - Camillio Suazo, 1992 September 16; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 7)
  - Marcus Vigil, 1992 September 16; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 8)
  - Dominguita Vigil, 1992 September 17; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 9)
  - Priscilla Vigil, 1992 September 17; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 10)
  - Caroline C. Padilla, 1992 December 11; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 11)
  - Vicenta Vigil, 1992 December 11; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 12)
  - Joe G. Vigil, 1992 December 14; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 13)
  - Rumaldo Herrera, 1992 December 14; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 14)
  - Teresa Tapia, 1992 December 14; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 15)
  - Grace Mora, 1992 December 05; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 16)
  - Marcus Vigil, Joe G. Vigil, Jose Pino, 1992 December 05; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 17)
    Tesuque geography
  - Marcus Vigil, Jose Pino, 1992 December 05; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 18)
    Mapping
  - Virginia Leno, 1993 February 08; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 19)
  - Joe A. Pino, 1993 February 08; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 20)
  - Marie Vigil Dorame, 1993 February 08; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 21)
  - Helen Herrera, 1993 February 08; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 22)
    Interviewed and recorded by Sue Dorame
  - Emiliana Romero Samuel, 1993 February 09; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 23)
  - Marie Felix Quinlivan, 1993 February 10; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 24)
  - James Hena, 1993 February 10; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 25)
  - Paul Vigil, 1993 February 10; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 26)
  - Marie Veronica Vigil, 1993 February 10; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 27)
  - Eligio Vigil, 1993 February 10; Audiocassette (Cassette TES 28)
- Ute curriculum project
  - Ruth Cohoe, Elisa Pawwinnee, 1976 Fall; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel UCP 1)
    Uintah Basin, Utah.
    Interviewed and recorded by Norma Denver and Daisy Jenks
  - Velmon Johnson, 1976 October 27; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel UCP 2)
    Interviewed and recorded by Norma Denver in Whiteriver, Utah.
  - Rose Johnson, 1976 Fall; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel UCP 3)
    Interviewed and recorded by Norma Denver
  - Rose Johnson, 1976 October 13; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel UCP 4)
    Fort Duchesne, Utah.
  - Harrette Johnson, 1976 October 28; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel UCP 5)
    Tanapont and Ft. Duchesne, Utah.
  - Dwight Copperfield, 1976 November 03; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel UCP 6)
    Ft. Duchesne, Utah
  - Ethel Grant, 1976 November 02-03; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel UCP 7)
  - Ethel Grant, 1976 November 10; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel UCP 8)
    Ute Tribal Museum, Ft. Duchesne Utah.
    interviewed and recorded by Norma Denver
  - Ethel Grant, 1976 November 17; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel UCP 9)
  - Ruth Cohoe, Elise Powwinnee, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel UCP 10)
  - Rose Johnson, 1976 November 17; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel UCP 11)
  - Dick and Katy McKewan, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel UCP 12)
    Ft. Duchesne, Utah.
    Interviewed and recorded by Norma Denver. Translated by Daisy Jenks.
  - Dick and Katy McKewan, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel UCP 13)
  - Lucy Astha-Patterson, 1976 October; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel UCP 14)
  - Tommy Thompson, 1976 November 07; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel UCP 15)
  - Esther Jack, Effie Eaton, Helen Wash, 1976 November 22; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel UCP 16)
    Interviewed and recorded by Norma Denver.
  - Daisy Jenks, 1976 December 27; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel UCP 17)
  - Rebecca Cuch, 1976 December 28; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel UCP 18)
    Interviewed and recorded by Daisy Jenks.
  - Vessie Ioka Cesspooch, 1976 December 29; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel UCP 19)
- Indian Unity Caravan
  - Mad Bear, Tom Benaka, 'Warm South Wind', 1972 August 18; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel IUC 1)
    Prayer by: Mad Bear, Tom Benaka, and 'Warm South Wind' at the Indian Unity Caravan: West Jordan Park, West Jordan, Utah.
  - Tom Benaka, 'Warm South Wind', 1972 August 17; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel IUC 2)
    Tom Benaka and 'Warm South Wind' at the Indian Unity Caravan at West Jordan Park, West Jordan, Utah.
  - Mad Bear, 1972 August 17; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel IUC 3)
    Mad Bear at the Indian Unity Caravan at West Jordan Park, West Jordan, Utah.
  - Indian Unity Caravan, 1972 August 17; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel IUC 4)
    Recorded by Mary Ellen Sloan at West Jordan Park in West Jordan, Utah.
  - Indian Unity Caravan, 1972 August 17; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel IUC 5)
- Santa Ana Pueblo
  - Porfirio Montoya, 1979 November 27; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel SAP 1)
    Santa Ana Pueblo.
  - Porfirio Montoya, 1980 January 16; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel SAP 2)
    Aboriginal boundary.
    Interviewed and recorded by Floyd Montoya
  - Porfirio Montoya, 1980 January 16; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel SAP 3)
    Migration story of the Santa Ana Pueblo Indians.
    Interviewed and recorded by Donna Pino and Thomas Huebben.
  - Porfirio Montoya, 1980 January 21; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel SAP 4)
    Migration story of the Santa Ana Pueblo Indians (continued from SAP 3).
    Interviewed and recorded by Donna Pino and Thomas Huebben
  - Leo Pena, 1980 January 24; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel SAP 5)
    Santa Ana history.
    Interviewed and recorded by Ben Pena and Floyd Montoya
  - Santa Ana/San Felipe overlap, 1980 January 25; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel SAP 6)
    This tape contains information on the overlapping boundaries of the Santa Ana Pueblo Indians and the San Felipe Pueblo Indians. Offering information are: Porfirio Montoya, Elijio Montoya, Governor Lawrence Montoya, Lt. Gov. Louis Armijo, Roy Montoya, Andy Leon, Floyd Montoya, Tom Luebben, and Richard Hughes.
  - Santa Ana/San Felipe overlap, 1980 January 25; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel SAP 7)
    Discussion of Santa Ana/San Felipe Pueblo Boundary overlap. Offering information are: Porfirio Montoya, Elijio Montoya, Clyde Leon, Gov. Lawrence, Lt. Gov. Louis Armijo, Alfonso Garcia, Albert Montoya, Vicente Armijo, Roy Montoya, Andy Leon, Floyd Montoya, Tom Luebben, and Richard Hughes.
  - Porfirio Montoya, 1980 February 04; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel SAP 8)
    Migration of Santa Ana Pueblo Indians.
    Interviewed and recorded by Donna Pino, Thomas Luebben, and Floyd Montoya.
  - Christo Garcia, Floyd Montoya, 1980 February 04; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel SAP 9)
    The general history of Santa Ana Pueblo.
  - General History of Santa Ana, 1980 February 05; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel SAP 10)
    Trip with delegates from Jemez, Zia, and Santa Ana to cover the Ojo Del Espiritu Santo grant.
  - Jose Ramond Sanchez, Felix Garcia, Floyd Montoya, 1980 February 07; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel SAP 11)
    Albuquerque Indian Schools (1910). General history of Santa Ana.
  - Porfirio Montoya, 1990 February 11; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel SAP 12)
    Pueblo livestock, herding in the Rio Rancho area.
  - Porfirio Montoya, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel SAP 13)
    Pueblo livestock herding.
  - Eudora L. Montoya, Floyd Montoya, 1980 February 26; 1980 February 28; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel SAP 14)
    Eudora L. Montoya discusses Pueblo pottery making and Pueblo Indian cooking. Floyd Montoya discusses his personal history, Sisters of Loretto School, and techniques of Pueblo pottery making.
  - Porfirio Montoya, Floyd Montoya, Thomas Luebben, 1980 March 10; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel SAP 15)
    Migration story from the Sandia Mountain to Tamaya, a portion of the secular form of government introduced by the Spaniards.
  - Porfirio Montoya, Floyd Montoya, Thomas Luebben, 1980 March 25; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel SAP 16)
    Migrations of Tamaya.
  - Truman Eustis, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel SAP 17)
    New England Association for Oral History meeting.
- Ute - Mountain Ute series I
  - Stanley C. Lyman, 1971 March 12; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT 1)
    Stanley C. Lyman; Ute singers from Ft. Duchesne.
    Recorded by Stanley Lyman
  - Stanley C. Lyman, 1971 March 12; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT 2)
    Stanley C. Lyman; Ute Singers from Ft. Duchesne.
  - Hall Taylor, 1986 March 27; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT 3)
    Four Tales told by Hall Taylor.
    Recorded by Floyd A. O'Neil
  - Hall Taylor, 1986 March 27; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT 4)
    This is a duplicate of item UMT 3.
  - Harry Dutchie, 1986 May 30; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT 5)
    Interviewed and recorded by Greg Thompson
  - Evalina Mills Lopez, 1986 May 30; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT 6)
  - Evaline Mills Lopez, 1986 May 30; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT 7)
    This is a continuation of UMT 6.
  - Norman Lopez, 1986 May 30; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT 8)
  - Leslie Hart et al, 1986 May 30; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT 9)
  - Paul Ute, 1986 June 26; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT 10)
  - Paul Ute, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT 11)
    Translation of item UMT 10.
  - Arlene Caspooch, 1986 June 26; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT 12)
    Interviewed and recorded by Victor Height and Floyd A. O'Neil
- Ute - Mountain Ute contract series II
  - Raymond Talk, Sr., 1990 December 07; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT Crt. 1)
  - Gladys Hammond, 1990 December 07; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT Crt. 2)
  - Susan Lehi, 1990 December; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT Crt. 3)
  - Maria Hight, 1990 December 07; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT Crt. 4)
  - Arthur Cuthair, 1991 January 07; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT Crt. 5)
    Interviewed and recorded by Floyd A. O'Neil and Winston Erickson
  - Lucy Shed Jacket Lopez, 1991 January 07; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT Crt. 6)
  - Molly Deer Bearshead, 1991 January 07; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT Crt. 7)
  - Miles M. Mills, 1991 January 07; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT Crt. 8)
  - Iris Salt, 1991 January 07; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT Crt. 9)
  - Albert Wing Sr., 1991 January 08; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT Crt. 10)
  - Clifford White Sr., 1991 January 08; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT Crt. 11)
  - Maude Washington, 1991 January 08; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT Crt. 12)
  - Tom Johnson, 1991 January 08; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT Crt. 13)
  - Frances Wall, 1991 January 09; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT Crt. 14)
  - Chloe Ute, 1991 January 00; Audiocassette (Cassette UMT Crt. 15)